{
    "id": "03f2cc42c21a4a10b3898f11a4ce65f2",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "........................... someone gives me a lift, I won't be able to reach office on time.",
            "description": "Unless means if not.",
            "answers": [
                "Unless",
                "If",
                "Whether"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c0e17dd713aa4cb0b12a042cb95905d7"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will come with you if you ...................................... for my drink.",
            "description": "In first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "pay",
                "paid",
                "have paid"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "38ebb2aa682a4a7e9a9e5646e90b5d43"
        },
        {
            "question": ".......................... you don't wear a coat, you may catch a cold.",
            "description": "We use if to express a condition.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Whether",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2fee3532b33a4a0b97bc7dc5748f95f0"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ........................... a cake if it is your birthday.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will bake",
                "would bake",
                "would have baked"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "986053a3cbb6403491cf30bec410c4e5"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ............................. in Bangkok, she may visit her cousins.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "cca071673de647c0ace20139aa42f786"
        },
        {
            "question": "I could buy a laptop, if I ................................. more money.",
            "description": "In type 2 conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and could / would + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "49f393eb29c447eb9cd45e5630cdf2dc"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ............................... the jackpot, what would you do?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "win",
                "won",
                "had won"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "20a49cb3aa8a4979acbba9b99be240cd"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ................................. fewer health problems if you stop eating junk food.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will have",
                "would have",
                "would have had",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e8ee2977d9fb4e089346066897997282"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I hadn't broken my leg, I .................................... hiking with my cousins.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will go",
                "would go",
                "would have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "b37adb97de3f476093afc5ccb7e621ac"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had his number, I ................................ him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will call",
                "would call",
                "would have called"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "140209a7de174453993d8ca0dd27f9f3"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you arrived early, you ................................. the show.",
            "description": "In type 2 conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "don't miss",
                "won't miss",
                "wouldn't miss"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "51cfb8a4689c4da5896940cb324adcea"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she had called, I ...................................",
            "description": "In type 3 conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will go",
                "would go",
                "would have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4476b3b76e8448c49093d847d125bbf6"
        }
    ]
}